metrophotochallenge.com 2010-12-11

# METRO Photo Challenge: Privacy policy

### General

The personal information collected on this website will be used to contact you if one of your photos wins a prize. Metro will not share your personal information with any third parties without your explicit prior consent. Metro and its affiliates will not use your personal information for purposes other than Photo Challenge marketing activities without obtaining your explicit prior consent.

### Using your name, age and city for promotional activity

Metro reserves the right to publish your photos, your name, and age for all promotional activity related to this competition. For example, photo of the day – every day for 10+ days in more than 17 countries we will publish a selected photo, along with the photographer's name, age and city. That also includes the publication of your photo, its title and your name in the photo album that will later be distributed to general public (please read Rules and Terms & Conditions).

### What personal information does Metro collect on this website?

Metro will collect your first name, surname, age, phone number and e-mail address. We may also require your mailing address. You cannot take part in the competition or prize draw without submitting this data.

### Will you receive any mailings after you register?

After registering online you will receive an e-mail from Metro that asks you to validate your e-mail address. The message will contain a link that you must click to validate your e-mail address. You only need to do this once. After each stage of the competition, you will receive an e-mail notification about the progress of the competition (a total of four e-mails). You will also receive an e-mail if you win a prize. We will only send you other e-mails (Photo of the Day, e-newsletter, notifications about other Metro promotions and projects) if you give us prior consent.

### Will Metro disclose the information it collects to third parties?

Metro will not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others unless you have given your explicit permission. Metro may also provide aggregate statistics about visitors to its websites for its partners and clients. These statistics will include no personally identifying information.

### Why does Metro use "cookies"?

“Cookies” are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. They make it possible for Metro to identify registered users without needing to ask for registration details every time you vote for an entry or every time you access the site. The website uses cookies to make the user experience easier and speed up some processes. 

### Personal data protection

As the Party responsible for the data processing through the Services, Metro hereby undertakes to introduce any necessary security measures to guarantee confidentiality of such data. Metro likewise undertakes to disclose to users each and every use of the data contained in the consultation and in addition to provide a privacy policy on all those pages hosted, in compliance with the rules and regulations related to the right to privacy and protection of data of a personal nature. Metro acknowledges and warrants that  it complies with all and any legal requirements set forth in Data Protection Laws. 

Metro likewise hereby expressly undertakes to use such data for the sole purposes mentioned above. Furthermore, Metro: (a) does not carry out “spam” or any other mass advertisement activity that has not been requested; (b) does not send direct advertisements; (c) permits at any time, through on-line or off-line means, any user revoke his or her consent to the storage of their data.

Submitting the personal data by each participant means the expressed and unequivocal recognition of the following: (i) that Metro may process through him or her through any other person designated the management of all personal data; (ii) that Metro may incorporate that data into its file or files.  
The participant will be able to exercise his/her rights of access, modification, cancellation or opposition of his/her information by requesting it via the email address in the Contact section.
